I'm not saying everything
I've done was right.
I did the Spirit of Origin's bidding,
murdered countless people,
and even took the life of a close friend.
And then, to rid the world of that Spirit,
I'll leave behind a mountain of corpses.
I'm a devil. An enemy of humanity.
I kill, kill, and kill some more.
A "nightmare" of endless death.
If there really is an afterlife,
I'm bound for the lowest level.
But I don't care.
Not if I can slay the
Spirit of Origin, Mio Takamiya,
by my own hand.
Takamiya...?
I'm going to redo everything.
Bring all that's happened back to zero.
But for that, I need the power you hold!
With your power,
I know I can change history!
History...?
If I go into the past and erase
the Spirit of Origin,
I'll never become a Spirit.
Sawa's death... and everyone else's deaths
will simply not happen.
Even my devouring of you
should cease to take place.
Shido, I'm begging you!
Please, let me borrow
your power to make it so!
Of course, there's nothing
I can offer as a fair trade.
After all, it doesn't change
the fact I'm asking for your life.
So, the least I can do...
H-Hey!
...is to give you my everything,
save for my Spirit power.
Found you!
Oh, my!
Were you two having fun?
Sorry about that!
Don't let us stop you!
It'd be sad to die
without "knowing" a girl.
My, my.
For being a bunch of phony Spirits,
you sure have some nerve.
Oh? You're calling us phony?
Sounds like you're
insulting Father to me.
Unforgivable!
Zaphkiel, Zayin!
Kurumi? Kurumi!
Yet another failure?
That's quite curious.
Seems odd to me knowing Beelzebub
set her up for success.
If inability isn't the reason for failure,
I'd love to hear what is.
Wow, Ellen. You're not holding back.
Well, then. What do you have to say?
Oh? She's asking for it.
You've failed more than anyone.
Such a mad grandma.
Being old must suck.
Excuse me?!
Get this, Father!
People get in our way!
"Nightmare," was it?
Such a nuisance! What's her problem?!
If not for her, we could've killed
Shido Itsuka dozens of times!
Hmm... The Worst Spirit
protecting a human.
What strange times we're in.
But it seems too implausible,
even for Nightmare.
She's defied every single plan of ours.
Perhaps she knows what we plan to do,
even before we do it.
Were our plans leaked?
No...
Not our plans,
but our attacks themselves.
Kurumi, are you okay? Kurumi!
Sorry to keep you waiting, Shido.
Kurumi...?
You're Kurumi's... clone?
Yes. The me before you is sleeping.
Please let her rest for a while.
She's completely exhausted.
She was tired to begin with,
not to mention all the fighting.
What do you mean?
To get straight to the point, Shido,
you have already died.
Huh?
To be precise, you should be dead.
No, I suppose I should say
it's possible you died.
All right, Kurumi. I came as promised.
This morning, I noticed something:
You've changed a bit, Shido.
Eh?
You look like you've matured.
Though, I suppose it's expected with all
the carnage you've lived through.
D-Don't make fun.
Anyway, what's this condition of yours
for sealing your Spirit power?
Okay, okay. I'll tell you.
I...
Shido!
--Shido!
Hey, don't interfere.
If anyone, I think we're
the ones interfering.
Wh-What's with these guys?!
Confusion. Who are you?!
Metatron!
Get lost!
Zaphkiel!
It's over!
No!
Shido!
Here you go, me.
Zaphkiel, Daletto!
Are you all right, me?
Yes.
That's...?
Tohka and the others fighting.
They've gone inverse, haven't they?
Inverse...
It's no surprise, with Shido
killed before their very eyes...
--Me.
That's...
Yes, yes. We barely made it out.
I couldn't leave him behind.
Daletto.
Shido! Shido!
As I thought, it's no use.
Daletto's bullet reverses time,
but it can't bring back
a life that is lost.
Have I... failed?
I failed Shido, and failed at erasing
the Spirit of Origin, too?
Shido...
Huh?!
Z-Zaphkiel!
What's going on?
My sixth bullet, Vav, is restored?
Why? Vav sends a mind into the past.
But it was broken during
the fight with Kotori...
Ever since, we haven't
been able to use it!
Could it be...?!
Huh? I don't follow.
After my fight with Kotori,
but before I had left,
I gave you a kiss as thanks for saving me.
When that happened, I believe
my sixth bullet, Vav, was sealed.
In other words...
Though not fully,
it was at that point
that I opened my heart to you, Shido.
I was unable to use Vav
not because Zaphkiel was broken,
but because part of my Spirit power
had been sealed by that kiss.
Just now, by kissing him again,
has that power returned to me?
Me's... Please die for Shido's sake.
Yes, yes. With pleasure.
Our lives are fleeting anyway.
Use us to your heart's content.
If it means saving Shido...
...I'll gladly visit the other side.
You, being me...
...should know we wouldn't refuse.
Then, I ask that you come with me
on an endless journey of death.
Zaphkiel, Vav.
"Tengu City"
"February 8    Thursday"
Seems like it worked.
And so, from February 8th till today,
we've been protecting you, Shido,
without your knowledge.
The first attack was thwarted
thanks to help from Mana.
--Two hundred and four.
--Huh?
That's how many times since February 8th
you've fallen into DEM's hands.
On the morning of February 10,
they even attacked you at home.
And many more times, over and over.
Each time, I've kissed you to regain Vav
and send my mind into the past.
It has strained my heart.
Repeating the same days so many times
has pushed my psyche to the limits.
So, Shido...
For now, please allow me to rest.
Why didn't you just
devour me at the start?
I mean, that's way easier for you
than repeating everything 204 times.
Please don't ask something so thoughtless.
My feelings... for you.
It sounds like you enjoyed your little
chat while I was busy sleeping, me.
I'm sorry about that, Shido.
This younger "me" is being foolish.
Kurumi!
Please don't get me wrong.
I only helped you so I don't lose all
the Spirit power you've sealed thus far.
Y-Yeah. I get it.
Let's leave it at that for today.
Until next time.
Hey, Kurumi!
Kurumi...
You said things you shouldn't have, me.
If I may, I fail to see
what the problem is.
My resolve--my hardship has been
anything but ordinary.
It's enough to fall asleep in front
of Shido, albeit for a moment.
That being the case,
who can fault me for telling him?!
And besides, given all the times
I've saved Shido,
surely he holds feelings
of gratitude towards me!
What bad could come of it?!
He might get the wrong idea.
Huh?
It might seem like he's touched
my heart or something!
You're right, I suppose so!
It feels like you're mocking me.
So, what should we do now?
Even if we got through today,
we don't have much time.
DEM Industries will attack again shortly.
I only have so much energy
and strength. At this rate...
I'm afraid you're right.
Troubled, are we, Kurumi?
Phantom...
Not a very warm welcome.
I only came to give some advice.
Welcome you? You best think twice
before making jokes.
So cold. Haven't I helped you by
providing information all those times?
Wasn't I the one who told you
about Shido Itsuka?
Ah, I see. You know, don't you?
That's too bad. I really did
come to give you advice.
Zaphkiel, Zayin!
Whoops, I let my guard down.
So, this is your true form, is it?
Yes. I didn't expect to be stripped of
my temporary form so easily.
That's Kurumi for you.
Ms. Murasame...
Is that how it is?
Yes, yes, it's all falling into place!
Me's!
There's no hell deep enough
for the likes of you.
--Shido!
--Relief, Shido!
Shido, you worried us!
Yeah, sorry.
But it's okay, I'm all right. Don't worry.
Kotori, can we locate Kurumi?
Well, Reine?
No. She's missing at the moment.
I'll keep searching.
Yeah, please do.
Guys, we need to talk.
About all that's happened...
and everything Kurumi's done for me.
I need everyone's help!
This time, it's my turn to save her!
"Episode 12:
'Cycle of Salvation.'"
Spirits: Special designation disaster
beings that exist in a critical space.
The origin of Spirits... The mystery of
Shido Itsuka... All shall become clear.
Date A Live 5, planned for production!